# **KAYLA WIGGINS**

Phone: (248) 470-5594 wiggikay@umich.edu

https://wiggikay.github.io/KWHome/

#### **ABOUT ME**

I'm a highly driven Junior currently pursuing a degree in Film, Television & Media with hopes of pursuing a dual degree in Information. My long-term goal is to have a research paper published and make tangible contributions to the field of HCI. That involves pursuing a master's degree! I'm also interested in the way that film acts as a powerful record of history and humanity throughout time, and the way that media acts as an ever-changing mode of communication and information sharing between people. My intended majors reflect the passions I've developed throughout my time here at Michigan and I'm excited to find new ways to connect the two disciplines.

#### **EDUCATION**

**BS** University of Michigan, FTVM

Ann Arbor, Michigan Junior (expected 2021) 2017 - Present

# WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Software Engineering Intern, ProQuest**

May 2020

This summer I will be working at ProQuest in a small agile team of professionals and other interns, supporting the product teams with software development, integration, and testing. I will assist with software debugging and understanding root cause and reproducibility, provide test results and support engineers providing break/fix service, as well as develop procedures, processes, and scripts to address business and product needs.

# Research Team Lead, CROMA Lab, University of Michigan

2017 - Present

Advisor: Walter Lasecki

- **Hybrid Teams** (on-going) Team Lead Our goal, at a high level, is to research the effects of introducing AI agents with varied ML models into a Human/AI team, given some classification task, in order to find out if the human worker is capable of maintaining an adequate mental model of their AI teammates or master the given classification task.
- **Expresso** Research Assistant an application that allows web developers to create responsive interfaces by defining keyframes.

## **Academic Innovations Fellow, University of Michigan**

2019 - Present

Advisor: Sean Patrick

In the Academic Innovations Lab, we coordinate and produce all of U of M's online course content for learners on campus and across the globe. I'm involved in the production process

which involves recording interviews, lectures, b-roll, etc. as well as the post-production work of editing. Also, my work includes creating and animating the graphics that Academic Innovations use to advertise their courses on social media.

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming**: C++ (3 yrs.), Python (1 yr.), HTML & CSS (4 yrs.), JavaScript & jQuery (4 yrs.), SQLite (1 yr.), PHP (1 yr.)

Applications: Adobe After Effects, Photoshop, Premiere Pro, R, Final Cut Pro, Adobe XD

**Other Skills**: Experience with research design and methodology, experience with UX testing such as A/B testing and usability testing, leadership abilities, team-oriented

## CLUBS & LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE & VOLUNTEER WORK

- Student Teacher [Arts/Coding] for Seven Mile community outreach program, which provides free music, arts, and coding lessons to children in the Detroit area.
- Member of Girls Who Code Loops, social computing and community outreach club
- STEMulation 2019 Group Leader, a yearly STEM exploration event coordinated by NESBE for high school students from underrepresented backgrounds